Guide to the Wilfred Stone research collection relating to E.M. Forster M1729
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wilfred Stone research collection relating to E.M. Forster
circa 1900-1977
M1729
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
3 linear feet (2 record storage boxes)
Included in the collection are articles and fugitive pieces, 1946-1977; reviews of The cave and the mountain, 1966; correspondence, and perhaps most interesting, some 16 folders of photographs totaling over 300 photos.
Stone, Wilfred Healy, 1917-
Scope and Content
Included in the collection are articles and fugitive pieces, 1946-1977; reviews of The cave and the mountain, 1966; correspondence, and perhaps most interesting, some 16 folders of photographs totaling over 300 photos.
Biographical/Historical Note
Stone wrote The cave and the mountain; a study of E. M. Forster, which was first published in 1966. Edward Morgan Forster was an English novelist, short story writer, essayist and librettist.
Access to Collection
Open for research. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Wilfred Stone, 2010. Accession 2010-002.
Forster, E. M. (Edward Morgan), 1879-1970; Stone, Wilfred Healy, 1917-
Container List
- Clippings, Circa 1960-1975
  - Reviews of The Cave and the Mountain, Circa 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folders 1-4)
  - Articles pertaining to E. M. Forster, Circa 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folders 5-10)
- Correspondence: ~70 letters to Wilfred Stone pertaining to The Cave and the Mountain, Circa 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folders 11-15)
- List of collection contents, annotated in detail by Wilfred Stone (Box 1)
- Photographs: E. M. Forster with friends and relatives; Forster literary locales in England, Italy, Egypt, and India. (Box 1, Folders 16-30)
- Publication materials: Short notices, letters, etc. relating to publication of The Cave and the Mountain (Box 1, Folders 31-33)
- Audio-visual materials relating to E. M. Forster (Box 2)
  - "Forster Country: E. M. Forster audio-visual programme" produced by Stevenage Museum, Hertfordshire. Includes 6 p. typed commentary, Circa 1970s
  - Audio Learning discussion tape on E. M. Forster, with Wilfred Stone and Oliver Stallybrass., 1972
  - Slides pertaining to research for The Cave and the Mountain, Circa 1960s
  - Minolta flash kit in zippered vinyl case, Circa 1960s